RG 062:015, Town of Bridgeport
Connecticut State Library
Town of Bridgeport records
circa 1917-1997, bulk 1938-1966
Connecticut State Library
Bridgeport (Conn.)
306 cubic feet
Welfare case files, circa 1917-1997, bulk 1938-1966.
RG062_015
2013-044
Historical Note
Bridgeport, Fairfield County, Town established in May 1821, City incorporated May 1836, Parent Towns: Fairfield and Stratford
Scope and Content
Welfare case files, circa 1938-1997, bulk 1938-1966. insane and tuberculosis case files, circa 1917-1940; case log books, 1942-1997; animal bites log book, 1942-1976; childrens tuberculosis log book, 1972-1977; tuberculosis log book, 1971-1977; salaries and wages log books, 1921-1957.
Arrangement
The welfare case files are arranged numerically by case number. Boxes 1 and 2 have later files from the 1970s to 1990s with older files mixed in.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport
Places:
Bridgeport (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Restrictions on Access
Welfare files and log books (Accession 2013-044) are restricted by Connecticut General Statutes §1-210(b)(10), §17b-90, §42-471, and §45a-754. The salaries and wages log books are open.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The welfare files and log books in accession 2013-044 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library from the City of Bridgeport Social Services Department on April 1, 8, 15, 23, 2013.
Container List
- Welfare Department records, circa 1917-1997, bulk 1938-1966; 306 cubic feet; 2013-044
  This entire series is restricted except for the 3 volumes of salaries and wages log books.
  - Welfare case files, circa 1917-1938 (Box 1-301)
    Arranged by case number
    Boxes 1 and 2 contain case files that date from the 1970s to 1990s with low-numbered case files. There are older files mixed in. Box 57 was not transferred to the Connecticut State Library. Box 301 contains files that were loose prior to transfer.
  - Insane and tuberculosis case files, circa 1917-1940 (Box 302-304)
    Tuberculosis cases are contained in Box 304
  - Case log book, 1942 August 21 - 1958 April 28 (Volume 305)
    Lists case numbers and names for cases 61920 to 65500 that date from August 21, 1942 to June 16, 1949. There is a separate listing of numbers 5173 to 7649 that date from March 5, 1957 to April 28, 1958.
  - Case log book, 1958 April 29 - 1969 March 27 (Volume 306)
    Lists case numbers and names for cases 65501 to 71643 that date from April 29, 1958 to March 27, 1969. There is a separate listing of numbers 6750 to 88076 that date from December 8, 1961 to December 17, 1962.
  - Case log book, 1969 April 1 - 1975 January 14 (Volume 307)
    Lists case numbers and names for cases 71655 to 83642.
  - Case log book, 1975 January 14 - 1980 November 6 (Volume 308)
    Lists case numbers and names for cases 83643 to 102223.
  - Case log book, 1980 November 6 - 1986 March 24 (Volume 309)
    Lists case numbers and names for cases 102224 to 122074.
  - Case log book, 1986 March 24 - 1991 August 26 (Volume 310)
    Lists case numbers and names for cases 122075 to 140822.
  - Case log book, 1992 March 11 - 1997 November 4 (Volume 311)
    Lists case numbers and names for cases 143584 to 160325
  - Animal bites log book, 1952-1976 (Volume 312)
  - Childrens tuberculosis log book, 1972-1977 (Volume 313)
  - Tuberculosis log book, 1971-1977 (Volume 314)
  - Salaries and wages log book, 1921-1929 (Volume 315)
  - Salaries and wages log book, 1931-1949 (Volume 316)
  - Salaries and wages log book, 1949-1957 (Volume 317)